When the heat of trial hits us, our real self surfaces.
Are you with me?
One can come to me and say, "This man is gently and very nice".
I would say, "Oh, he is nice? I want to see his track record, where he is coming from,
the battles he has fought."
When the heat of trial, temptation, affliction hits you, your real self surfaces.
Your real self surfaces.
"He is quiet, gentle, very humble; what a wonderful man." - I say, "Aha!"
"He is wonderful, quiet, gentle; hmm."
Your real self surfaces...
Those things you keep to yourself; only you and God.
And people keep saying you are very nice, "What a wonderful, quiet man",
but many things you keep to yourself.
Only you and God; your Creator knows.
You keep hiding it, "Yes, sir... "
What are those things we keep to ourselves?
Those elements like jealousy, bitterness, anger, envy, resentment, hatred -
you have the ability to keep those things to yourself.
"I heard that you have been promoted to GM of the company; wonderful - congratulations",
whereas inside you is not a congratulation.
Inside you is, "Why not me? Why him? I know him. Why not me?"
These are the things we keep to ourselves.
When the heat of trial, temptation, hits us, our real self surfaces.
Each time I look at you – your appearance – I need to look at your heart.
Some say, "I'm a Christian. I've been doing good. I've been very nice to people."
The manner you forgive, restore and help, in the same manner you will be helped and forgiven.
So, you show that what you are doing to people is not from your heart.
The manner you help, forgive and restore another person,
in the same manner you will be restored, helped and forgiven.
Therefore, whatever you are doing, do it with all your heart.
Look at everyone here today; you are seated as if you really mean what you are here for.
How many of us actually need Jesus?
Oh how I love Jesus
Because He went for me
He went for us; because He is no longer on the cross.
You really love Jesus?
In good times you are saying, "I love Jesus in good times" but in hard time... - question mark.
You love Jesus?
In good times, when there is a testimony, money in the pocket, food on the table; you love Jesus,
but when there is no money in the pocket, no food on the table; question mark.
Oh how I love Jesus
Because He went for me
When there is no money in the pocket; question mark.
When there is money; you love Jesus - indeed.
You love Him.
When the heat of trial, disappointment, failure, sickness, disease, affliction, setback hits,
your real self surfaces.
"I do come to a church all the time. I pay my tithe. I have stopped smoking. I don't know why this happened to me.
Why all this; I don't know. Oh my God. Look at my friend; he never worships God or goes to church -
see him, he is fine. Oh my God." - you begin to see Jesus in the bad light.
When you see people dancing in the church; you can spot those who have testimonies today.
Some people do like this... - you know he has a testimony.
When some people are like this, "Inner my heart Lord..."...
Because your life is ruled by your blessing.
If there is blessing you are happy and if there is no blessing...
- Your life is ruled by your what?
- (Blessing.)
By your blessing.
OK, where is Jesus?
"Jesus - in good and hard times", tell your neighbour.
Where is Jesus?
Jesus – in good and hard times.
If you know Jesus in good times, you are a part-time Christian.
If you don't know Him in hard times, you are a part-time Christian.
Jesus is not looking for part-time but full-time Christians.
Tell your neighbour, "If you know Jesus in good times and not in hard times, you are a part-time Christian".
Jesus is not looking for part-time Christians but full-time Christians.
You must know Him in good and hard times alike.
The way you help, you are helped.
The way you greet, the Spirit of God also greets you.
The way you forgive, you would be forgiven.
The way you love your neighbour, the same way you are being loved by the Spirit of God.
Can you see; each time you receive you know it is a reward, because He is a Rewarder.
If you are giving what you do not need, you will continue to receive what you do not need.
If you give what your life depends on, you will receive what your life depends on from Jesus.
He has no farm, house or office; He is your neighbour, your brother.
Whatever you do to the little among you, that you do unto God.
What have you done to your neighbour today?
How many people have you blessed today?
... and you are coming to God for blessing.
You know; you come from somewhere - if you look right you see poor, if you look left you see poor,
at your back you see poor, at your front you see poor.
What have you done today to your neighbour?
Nothing, but you are waiting to receive from God.
In my local language we say:
Eni keni ti iwo be ni'pa
Whoever you have ability
Lati se iranlowo fun o
To assist
Oun na leni'keji re ranti re
He is your neighbour remember them
You must love your neighbour as yourself.
Your neighbour may not share the same faith with you.
Your neighbour may not be a Christian but love first.
Love first.
Your pain must be my pain and your joy must be my joy.
When you begin to see life in this manner, you are getting to the centre of your own world.
You are not blessed only because of your family but today people use that blessing only to their families.
You are blessed to bless others, including your family.
Amen?
Let me take you to the Book of John 8.
Inner my heart
What do you thing I'm trying to say?
When I sing, I'm talking.
I'm not a singer; you know I can compose, but I'm preaching, prophesying.
When I say, "Inner my heart" I say I need your heart.
If we confess in our heart, "Jesus is my Lord", immediately you confess in your heart,
here, Jesus comes in to bring you the balance.
You are able to say the truth, and to listen to me with all your heart.
Here Jesus comes in to bring the balance.
As you are sitting, you can begin to engage your heart:
Lord Jesus, I am a sinner.
Come into my heart.
Wash me with Your precious blood.
Save my soul today.
Your heart can be engaged while you are listening to me.
Are you engaging your heart?
Hallelujah!
Yes.
In that Book of John 8 I take verse 3 there - it says:
"The teachers of the law and the Pharisees brought in a woman caught in adultery.
They made her stand before the group
and said to Jesus, 'Teacher, this woman was caught in the act of adultery.
In the Law of Moses commanded us to stone such woman. Now what do you say?'"
This is the question to Jesus.
They knew what to do by their law of Moses but they came to Jesus,
in order to have something to trap Him.
"They were using this question as a trap, in order to have a basis for accusing Him."
They were looking for a way of accusing Him; what they can do - this is an opportunity for them.
"But Jesus bent down and started to write on the ground with His finger.
When they kept on questioning Him, He straightened up and said to them,
'Let any one of you who is without sin be the first to throw a stone at her'."
Hallelujah, this is the question, this is what I'm saying here.
How can the kettle call the pot black – birds of the same feather -
when they are all one, used for cooking?
When you go by this, "Let any one who is without sin be the first"...
When we are offended, we feel hurt and blame the offender.
When we are offended, we feel hurt, embarrassed and blame our offender.
We always defend our bitterness, our anger.
We always defend our right – whether we are right or wrong – we are always there to defend
to justify our reason of doing what we are doing.
"This is a small boy, I trained him, I sent him to school; look at the insult he is passing to me."
This is you reason; inability to forgive - the reason why you won't forgive him.
"I trained him, I'm older than him..."
If that is the case, if by age, experiences in the world - I would not be the one to stand before you today -
we should look for someone else to come and address you.
... if by age and experiences out there, or by where we are coming from and what we have seen in life -
I should not be the one to stand here and address you.
We always defend our bitterness, anger and right to justify our reason or inability to forgive.
"Don't talk to me. You are living in a poor community. Do you know who I am? Please! No, he is illiterate"
It is at this point, Jesus advises us by saying, “How can the kettle call the pot black?”
How can the kettle call the pot black?
This means, "How can the kettle blame pot?"
How can you blame him?
How can anybody from over there come to blame anyone here, when you are birds of the same feather?
Remember your own weakness; you are not the right person to judge.
This is what Jesus referred to, when he bent down and wrote on the ground with his finger.
As they kept on questioning Him, the Bible says He straightened up and said to them,
"Let anyone of you without envy, unforgiveness, anger, bitterness, jealousy, pride
hold offence, or continue to absorb; keep blaming your neighbour for offence he has done to him."
Tell your neighbour, "Let anyone of you without envy, jealousy, pride, unforgiveness hold offence".
When you take your Bible to the Book of Luke 23 and go straight to the verse 34:
“Jesus said, ‘Father forgive them, for they do not know what they are doing’.”
That statement alone - what we are saying here, "Father forgive them".
Take note of the word, ‘them’ because it includes both the offender and offended.
It includes both the offender and offended -
the wrong and the right.
This should be Christians’ standard of life: Father, forgive them.
The word 'them' - take note; the wrong and the right.
This is why Jesus said, when he bent down to write on the ground with His finger, He said to them,
"Let anyone of you without envy, jealousy...".
He simplified the sin mentioned there.
He said, "Let anyone of you without sin..."
You say, "Sin - what is sin?"
Many of you may not even understand that, "just sin".
This is what the Bible said there, "just sin".
But, "Let anyone of you without envy, jealousy, bitterness, pride..." - those things you keep to yourself.
Only when the heat of trial and temptation comes, "Don't talk to me like that! I will deal with you!"
You say, "He? This man can talk like this?"
You say somebody offended you, "The man offends me. He used to be my servant; he is a millionaire now.
I helped him. He was working under me. In fact; look at the way he addresses me - in what way."
We always defend our bitterness to justify our reason, "He is my boy. I trained him." - this is to defend.
That is the reason why you have to say that.
That is why, "Yes, I have to say that. I helped him. I gave him capital to start a business.
Now, whatever he becomes today, he should be very careful."
Oh?!
... because of the capital you gave him.
What of Jesus?
He has no sin but your sin.
"Father, forgive them."
Take note of the word, ‘them’.
It includes both the offender and what?
The offended.
Tell your neighbour, “Let anyone of you who is without envy, jealousy, bitterness, unforgiveness, pride
hold offence.”
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is a reason why you shouldn't hold offence, whether you are right or wrong,
unless you are without envy, jealousy, pride, unforgiveness, bitterness, resentment, anger.
You are either a pot and your neighbour is a kettle, or you are a kettle and your neighbour is a pot;
birds of the same feather - pot and kettle used for cooking.
And I told you; the manner you forgive, restore, re-instate, greet, help, love another person,
you will be loved and forgiven by God.
By their fruit we shall know.
The manner you forgive, you will be forgiven.
Tell your neighbour.
The manner you forgive another person, you will be forgiven.
The manner you love another person, you will be loved.
The manner you restore your brother, you will be restored.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You know; what you are doing nowadays is not from your heart.
Sometimes when I come you say, "Good morning, Sir".
I say, "Oh, well done".
When you say, "Good morning", I say, "Good morning" - while you go I will look at your back.
I will say, "Well done, sir."
Some people would say, "Why the man of God said, 'well done'?"
I'm greeting you, I know you.
You raise your brother's hand up saying, "Winner!", while your heart will say, "Why not me?".
"Winner!", they call you and you say, "Winner!" - your heart will be saying, "Why not you?".
You invest in the brother, you give him millions; by the time he lefts, you sit down and look at yourself and say,
"How will I know that this boy will appreciate what I have done now? How this boy would pay me back?"
Our heart...
Match your action with your words.
Tell your neighbour.
- (Match your action with your words.)
- I cannot hear you.
(Match your action with your words.)
If you are able to match your action with your word, it comes from your heart.
You say, "Be healed!", and I say "Be healed!" - my heart is telling me "Which kind of a healing?".
That has nullified "Be healed!"
And I say, "Check yourself".
Reply: "I still feel pain."
When I say "Be healed!", I know what is going on in my heart.
"Be free! Amen."
Your heart keeps telling you, "Who is free? You are in a bondage."
A lot of voices are in our heart.
Match your action with your words.
This is the problem we have today.
You don't mean what you are saying, and you never mean what you are doing.
If you really mean...
While you sit down, you receive a phone call and hear that business you have been looking for; billion of dollars
- the man is just at the corner of your home, and he wants to see you in two minutes at your home.
You look around, "Where is usher? I'm pressed."
There is a language for every negative action.
Because you want to leave, you learn how to lie, "I'm pressed", and you are not pressed.
By the time you get there you say, "I'm looking for a restroom."
"OK, there is one there."
By the time you get to the restroom, you call your business partner back.
You know; that place is good for calling, "Hello. What are you telling me?"
"I say that in two minutes I will get to your house. If I don't see you, I'm leaving the country."
You hide your handset.
You will now plan what to say, so that they would open the gate for you.
You begin to plan, "What will I say now? I need to take something from the vehicle, it is very serious."
Because your coming here is not from your heart.
We have not been doing things from our heart.
And faith is of man’s heart.
Whatever that does not come from your heart is sin.
You can never see things clearly if your action is not from your heart.
Seeing things clearly can make us see beyond our present situation.
"This is disappointment."
But you don't know that that disappointment is meant to preserve you, prepare you,
strengthen your desire and determination for God.
It is meant to stop you for a while and re-arrange your future.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If your actions don't come from your heart, you cannot see things clearly.
You always see things on the surface.
What we are seeing now - if your coming here is not from your heart, we will only see,
"This man has a white beard. Is it dyed? What has happened? Look at him. He looks like my brother,
or my driver - just the same size. The man must be around fifty years of age.
He just wants to celebrate his birthday. Look at him; he is going to another direction. He will come back again.
What are those fruits? Can they give me one? I cannot get it."
Your heart will be jumping up and down.
Your heart will judge...; you will continue to be busy with your heart.
The heart that is busy cannot focus.
Oh my God; take that word.
Look at me; I am going this direction and something keeps telling me
that somebody is waiting for me at home.
The person - I don't know...
This is where I'm going to see somebody, but the heart keeps telling me, "Somebody is waiting for me at home
and I don't know whether I'll get there. I don't know if I meet the man at the office.
Last time he disappointed me. I don't know if he would disappoint me."
The heart keeps being busy; definitely you will lose focus.
You will probably not get here.
"Your heart is too busy." - tell your neighbour.
This is confusion in which we find ourselves.
Seeing clearly helps to see beyond our present situation.
... to preserve you, to prepare you, to strengthen your desire and determination, to stop you for a while
and re-arrange your future - this is your present situation, but you don't know, you just don't want it,
you do everything to remove it on your own.
The one that is waiting to re-arrange your future will say, "The man has gone; he didn't wait for me to arrange it.
I had to hold him to arrange his future before he moves. He has gone."
This is for you.
This is Jesus for you.
He asked the man at the pool of Bethesda, "What can I do for you? You want Me to pray for you?"
He didn't just grab the man and started praying, "I want to deliver you!" - no.
He needs your faith.
He needs your genuine willingness.
Our genuine willingness plus God’s ability work miracle.
If you are not and not ready to be genuine, no matter the power... - there is nothing.
He says, "I will make you fishers of men", if you what?
If you follow!
If you don't follow, He cannot make you to.
You have a role to play.
He says, “I will make you fishers of men
Fishers of men
I will make you fishers of men
If you follow Me"
That is the condition.
It is not all up to God and certainly, it is not all up to us.
It’s not all up to you; certainly, it is not all up to God.
Your genuine willingness and God’s ability work out things.
"If you follow Me"
If you don't follow Him...
The title: "How can the kettle blame pot?"
Tell your neighbour.
Again.
You may be the kettle, your neighbour may be the pot -
birds of the same feather, used for cooking.
The way out:
if you are without envy, jealousy, unforgiveness, bitterness, resentment, hurt, anger,
you can hold offence.
I’m very sure, here in this world, before you can see anyone without envy,
jealousy, unforgiveness, bitterness, resentment, anger, hurt, you will go to Heaven.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is why we should not hold offence, including me.
Holding offence is evidence that you are without any of these.
Let me pray with you, so that this message can have a place in your heart.
I pray this message finds a place in your heart.
(Amen.)
Say, “Find a place in my heart.”
I cannot hear you.
(Find a place in my heart.)
Because it is a very serious issue.
The world is like this because of offence.
Your life is like this because of offence.
You can never have a way out, without stopping to hold offence.
No way out; I'm telling you.
Because if you get deliverance now, and you get delivered, and you see your offender,
you will lose your deliverance.
Immediately, you will lose your blessing.
"Ah, this is a man I don't want to see. This is this woman. I will not take this call; this is a foolish man."
You are losing your blessing.
You will receive your deliverance, blessing, healing but to maintain this healing, stop holding offence.
Tell your neighbour.
You will receive healing, deliverance, blessing.
To maintain these blessing, stop holding offence.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The God that says, “Thou shall not lie” says, “Thou shall not kill” - the same God.
If you have lied, you have killed.
Why are you holding offence any longer?
Because you are without envy, unforgiveness, bitterness, hurt, anger;
that is why you are holding offence.
Can that be?
I pray this message finds a place in your heart,
in Jesus Christ’s name.
Thank You, Jesus.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated.
I'm free.
If you are free too, let me see your hand.
If the Spirit of God has touched you...
And you can begin to give a call; people you need to call - any opportunity you have,
- "I just want to say hi, I'm so so so..."
- "You call me?"
- "Yes, I call you. I've been praying for you. I love you so much..."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Send this message to you leaders.
If you have an opportunity to have a meeting with you leaders, please tell them,
“Holding offence is like committing a crime because unforgiveness imprisons us.
It puts us in the prison, cage."
You just find that there is a limit on what you can do.
I can't do this - there is a limit.
It puts us in the prison.
And what is not done well is not done at all.
Unforgiveness is too dangerous for your future.
Don’t pretend to forgive; don’t pretend to love.
Like I have said, the manner you love is the manner you will be loved.
The manner you forgive is the manner you will be forgiven.
Whatever you want to do, let it come from your heart.
God is the Rewarder.
If you continue to blame others, you will never repent.
"Ah yes, he is very rude to me" - you will never repent.
Accept everything, "Yes, this is wrong. OK. I know I'm the one."
Because we are not fighting the flesh and blood; blaming others you will never repent.
God often uses anything.
You might be sitting, somebody would just come and start beating you.
"Ah, what have I done?"
Remember you are a Christian - you better run, leave the place.
Don't retaliate because you don't know why this has happened.
Everything, "Why God?"...
God often uses anything - think about that.
What is anything?
So many things have been used in the past to prepare you but you failed.
I can give you some good examples.
Position of some of you was overtaken by "fire".
You were in a position, and your junior was promoted to be your head, your boss.
You now say, "Eh? I serve God. I fast and pray. I'm always in the church. How can my junior,
whom I gave instructions, can be promoted to be my boss? Oh no; by fire."
You run to a witch-doctor.
You say, "This one is my junior - he was promoted and is my boss now. He is the one giving me instructions."
The witch-doctor will say, "What do you want me to do?"
"By fire, by fire."
You are given a powder.
Since he now became your boss, you have to clean the table for him - you drop the powder there.
That is the end.
One month, two months - you take over the position.
You don't know that...
Look, it is too early to say that the man is blessed.
The beginner is not the owner but the finisher.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
These are the lessons we should learn.
Many heroes collapsed; great men, the rich, the wealthy...
The beginner is not the owner but the finisher.
If you don’t finish well, everything you lived for is gone and the history about you is erased.
The evil that men do lives after them.
Many of you have been prepared for a generation yet unborn, just like apostles -
they were prepared for the generation yet unborn, so that when they die,
their work will live for the generation yet unborn.
This is what we are seeing now.
Your exit; anytime you behave remember your exit.
Always think about where your thought, attitude, behaviour will be credited to your account.
Our account is in our future, not now.
You are living, working now.
What we are doing now will be credited to our future.
What are you doing now that will be credited to your future?
If you are doing evil now, that evil will be credited to your future.
Are you doing good now?
The good you are doing now will be credited to your future -
you will find them in the future, where that physical strength is no longer there.
Let us remember our future.
My future is my life.
That is life.
Let me suffer now and enjoy in the future.
But enjoying now and suffering in future - that is...
How many of us; but we are not ready to suffer now and enjoy in future.
So, what you are going through - and you are running for to the witch-doctor, try to cut the journey -
which is to prepare you for the future.
This is what I have said.
God often uses anything to preserve, prepare, strengthen our desire and determination,
to stop us for a while and arrange our future.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
He is arranging your future.
Anything can be used to arrange your future; sickness, disappointment.
Those things will come but you need those experiences.